

Dwight Johnson

Represented by Creative Circle (323) 930-2333

SUMMARY

During each of my summer vacations from high school, my first real job was to install and image thousands of computers for my local school district. Meanwhile, during the school year - I would usually be found in the journalism room. There, my role was developing the school's newspaper using QuarkXpress as the writer, photographer, managing editor and finally editor in chief. Now, almost two decades later, I'm still very much in love and have a passion for all things media and tech: graphic design, photography, web development, branding, typography, video, and pop culture.

WORK EXPERIENCE

9/2015 - 7/2017 Canto: Marketing Manager - Full-Time (now just occasionally contracting) - SoMa San Francisco, CA Marketing Automation (Marketo), email html responsive development, multisite Wordpress website management, landing page design, planning/design for conferences, social media management, advertising, Camtasia tutorials, graphic design, Adobe CC Illustrator, Photoshop, raw photography, sales collateral PDFs, and WalkMe development.

7/2015 - 8/2015 Interactive Data Corp: Senior Web Developer - Contract, Hayward, CA

Filling in for the main web developer in the marketing department. My tasks included uploading webinars to the dev/production server in ASP.NET along with updating content on a proprietary CMS as well as assisting with the transition to a more modern open source wordpress website.

2013-2014 Better Business Bureau: Communications Specialist - Sacramento, CA:

The BBB has many different office locations throughout the USA. The entire network of offices is based on one website with each subdomain being different – I was hired to help update the website; mostly making certain pages were responsive, designing graphics as well as email templates for internal and external communications.

02/2012-10/2013 Proven Business Services: Media Director – Sacramento, CA

Being a very small start-up, my role was vast and I wore many, many hats. Mostly my job entailed me designing web pages, developing/maintaining the different brands as well as preparing for many conferences and trade-shows. This is also where I started to use GIT for front-end design of a C# app.

2012 sueforsupervisor.com Political Campaign: Communications Director - Nevada City, CA

With my second political campaign – I was in charge of the overall brand and web/print communications for the Sue for Supervisor campaign. I was also in charge of photography for Sue and different events.

2010 barrypruett.com Political Campaign: Communications Director - Nevada City, CA

Being my first political campaign, I had to not only design the different print materials but also learn how to code a website!

FINISHED WEB PROJECTS

2015 rwalawpc.com - Law Office of Robert W. Ash WP

2015 dejohnsonplumbing.com – DE Johnson Plumbing *ROR*

2015 richardspowelldds.com – Richard S. Powell DDS WP

2014 burfdays.com - My final project for coding bootcamp ROR

2014 corcoranpruett.com - Corcoran Pruett LLP WP

2014 jordanisadore.com – Jordan Isadore Dance Portfolio **WP**

2013 barnlink.net – Barn Link *HTML/CSS*

2013 sheryllister.com - Sheryl Lister, Author WP

2013 audiotranferlab.com – CMS Web Dev/Designer WP

2012 saradujour.com – SARA du Jour Dance Satire WP

2012 barrypruett.com – Barry Pruett, JD HTML/CSS

2012 blackbirdcreek.net – Web Dev/Designer *HTML/CSS*

2011 humblepie.com – *HTML/CSS*

2010 crystalrainbowrockshop.com - HTML/CSS

WP = Wordpress Custom Theme Development **ROR** = Ruby on Rails and custom branding

EDUCATION

2009 **Bachelors of Arts**, Journalism, Humboldt State University

2014 Full-Stack / Ruby on Rails **Bootcamp Certificate** 3-month code bootcamp The Iron Yard Academy Houston, TX

2005-2006 **Study Abroad** University of the Basque Country, Spain

SKILLS

Adobe Creative Suite

Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Premier, Flash

Development

Wordpress.org, HTML, CSS(SASS), jQuery, Bootstrap, MVC, GIT, JavaScript, AJAX/JSON/RESTFUL APIS

INTERSHIPS

NBC Affiliate, **Live Newscast Assistant**, Humboldt County, CA The Union Newspaper, **Layout and Writer**, Grass Valley, CA NCTV, **Production Assistant**, Nevada City, CA